okay on ops copies they should tell not
automatically all right
is my phone did my phone rotate first i
unlock the rotation cool so we are
driving in a Cadillac ct-6 the only one
in the world with open pilots it's like
we bought this car with super cruise and
then we downgraded it we put open pilot
on it open Cory super Pinal yeah how do
I engage like cruise control yeah oh you
know what I like I can engage it
anywhere oh this is better
yeah and it goes by five you should not
lose your price those cars
Oh
but it is nice and super cruise because
you can engage it anywhere so super
cruise we'd have to wait a long time
before we could engage it let's see what
happens very cool between these lengths
oh you can really tell this doesn't lag
yeah oh man this is better
can you do both both what and you have
the savannahs disengage now Bend is know
send us what there are three pandas you
have a dependent owner that's can
messages yeah
yes now when you engage then the pond is
gonna blink a white but I can still do
this like it's cruise control yes
no we are engaged never there's a bug
see the bug what so oh no yeah I don't
enforce the cancellation you don't force
the cancellation I mean yeah the
cancellation of open pilot are a
superset of the custom yeah yeah so we
got we got to change that for that
release oh yeah I mean wait when I
started work on don't you - no well yeah
yeah guys but we got we got this
beautiful ct-6 surrounding a beautiful
open pilot we're gonna make it better
than super cruise by the end of the year
most of my job as CEO is saying the same
things over and over and over again
do you have way of imperative Emily
great well they don't
Obama wide open pilots have Emily Chloe
fixed how we fixed it why did it have
memory leaks well what's that been -
focus focus on what what this is all
right being better than super cruise on
those six cars is the focus of the year
the step better Twitter Stan on then to
your third definitely yes
yes that yes like as much dark as you
want so we have to limit the torque
artificial there's a special command you
sent into the steering controller that
puts it in superheroes mode and you can
get scary amounts of torque in super
cruise mode so the Cadillac has
redundant ECU's in the back for this
um so we've set up there are two pandas
back there doing proxy yeah so this is a
triple panda car guys pandas are so
versatile yes Oh bye pandas today shop
like I would buy in or three pandas
blocking messages they all boards all
right finally this light go forever
yeah but it's theory it says that but
experience okay Wow guys this this
actuator so good so this is GM's icing
oh man oh it doesn't wobble oh this is
cheating
no wonder super cruise is so good oh man
what were we talking part not anybody's
fault better we still have to go to the
highway it's literally like this it
doesn't wobble I mean I know well okay
okay there's a little wobble I keep my
hands very close to the wheel you know
we have some safety we don't know how
good it is it has not been extensively
tested but I'm not
it is it is daring right now
I'm gonna see what it's not it's not
like I don't know what's doing it well
they stand for a it's very temporary
yeah there must be a stay and we're in
we're in super cruise mode now
yeah I'm printing the stage so I know
yeah
all this cost this is so good
here's a lot better gonna do stop cars
oh yeah because we've left everything on
so I can do fusion oh my god oh that was
sickening Oh Ricardo creak creak creak
you'll replace it with ours okay yeah
GM GM just did a stop behind a stopped
car it was not a detection problem it
just stopped in such a sickening way
alright no more letting it do that I'm
telling you those supercruise has a
different supercruise has a different
acc it's Bank yeah it's better cuz it
doesn't do that I know I know you don't
know you know it's kind of true I mean
you desktop and go hang with you guys
stop it going our way and I felt it'd be
better I was GM's ACCC I don't know
they've only been busier nowadays on for
sure like dining is busy cities
expensive
well it's dinner they're gonna have to
say recovery Jack Therese just some crab
yeah yeah so FBC so the MPC is the
control algorithm that open pilot uses
to compute its trajectory it's much more
sophisticated than what everyone else is
doing except for I'm sure Tesla's NPC
you know yeah tests are just doing up to
say yes but they didn't have it at first
autopilot is have you say yeah
now before now but I mean notice what do
you want refer to we talking about silky
smooth
I don't know I mean I think some shoes
everything don't really apply it use
obviously I don't that I'm not for much
else to gets in there all that have a
standard callaloo
oh wow yeah it's like a holiday it's
just so much better yeah so seriously
the reason oh come on scrappy on our
cars as actuators yeah I mean if there's
definitely a lot of difference we'd all
come from different cars but yeah it's
like this feels very good
it's basically the only car that is
built with an activator that is meant to
be active
yeah compare this like the Toyota
actuators are so much worse
I got a feeling that Toyota performance
is because of the actuators
yeah yeah that me depreciable increase
my chatot yeah what's the focus for the
next to the man that is Hitler and that
could be that mr. Chris would do that
but Plato just need to compensate for
perfect return yes
they don't think the rifle
it's not supercruise it's not as good
yeah wait can I unable supercruise no
because it's like yeah I mean you can
but that does nothing so we're blocking
the good intelligent control
oh man that's a lot of tour well the
kids are unavailable but yeah now did it
oh no no so now it's back that's
interesting okay
Wow oh yeah this almost supercruise
makes mistakes so Chris doesn't make
mistakes
that's what we forget supercruise would
have disengaged a long time ago
yeah me at least it's always available
it is always available to be removed in
a later version no scarcely we won't be
as aggressive a super curse but we're
gonna start doing confident stuff and if
it's not confident
but
if we have to tune our threshold for
what sort of disengagement will tolerate
GM will tolerate nothing but they're
extremely conservative of the layman
gage
yeah oh this is like perfect penis it's
wobbling now the link supercruise does
this camera yeah oh the hold really it's
just it's just upsetting that the whole
thing is the actuators yeah I mean we're
pretty lightweight the plan totally
well that's just yeah so let's just
improve right yeah exactly the decision
aids are never getting into our be being
gave the perfect for this phone is gonna
be excited
yeah guys like open pilot works like
flawlessly here
I mean dense fog on like an exit ramp
like perfect
except they actually thought shit well
when the actuators aren't shitty it
doesn't move out of the lane and when it
doesn't move out of the lay that doesn't
have model failures yeah I mean that's
really what it comes down to it does be
done he says this is dangerous
torque yes the angle rate limited I did
it because otherwise it was like at the
way too bad you so much
where did you do it I can't keep my
hands real close to steering wheel yeah
I mean it's not like I can find it
obviously it will disengage eventually
yeah I mean you can put too much stock
so like sometimes it fights me and
sometimes it doesn't
yes never gives up fighting you changes
there okay so has a different state yeah
thinking getting the states right
I could be so much better let's stop
oh you may you hacked for autozone I
know you followed like if the time is
short yeah
none of us is gonna get the earth people
a come on about accidents possible
accidents oh no one's gonna get hurt
yeah my hands are literally touching the
steering wheel it's not gonna do
anything that fast
and if I step on like the gas its
disengaged how do I read you know which
is cancel days accidents don't happen
the first time you go out and test
something accidents happen the 30th time
when you think it's just safe you stop
paying attention and then you crash
cut it
yeah
what else let's go we say silent
pretty good though yeah I mean you just
it feels like it's just not gonna I
don't know like I feel like a lot of the
mistakes Oakland pilot makes where it
like pushes you out of the lane our do
do it loses the actuator for a little
bit and then just in general yeah in
general what I feel it does in general I
feel like a lot of the mistakes like
open pilot makes we're all like little
like lose it and then try to change
lanes yeah um our because the actuator
dies for like you know have a second
yeah yeah and then you get close and
then you close and yet it's like it's a
lane change yeah yeah no definitely
having a good as to later they keep you
centered helps yeah
the thing
here so we're not available for that it
was still staring yeah sometimes it
changes state and well one week once we
send the the alert is the other stays
there for a while even if recovered
and for example now
and I need to call her AG docks of
supercruise way they talk about torque
oh yeah
we need regulation that forces people to
open-source
their say Jenna nice throw
[Music]
whatever should have to open source a
safety monitor
would have prevented over maybe yeah
yeah
all right so we get a little wobble here
like there's per this wobble present but
much much less than like on the Toyota
nice sharp turn coming up guys so he
does
we found it it's false
yesterday good
I don't I think I was like oh so I get
it that I kappa i'm at their statement
they're a lot
oh yeah
yeah model for you
the lanes are right it was like way too
far to the left
well okay
so it tries to recover sometimes have
seen like if the mother is not like
self-consistent he thinks is recovered
but it's not recovering because it's not
consistent but I also have a pretty low
weight on the steer great cast so you
should recover quickly yes I know it's
wobbling
yeah I mean it's crazy this is even
fairly on tuned as well it's like
literally the first time that we
actually dive it in this configuration
and never thought yeah so it is amazing
I'm sure it's actuator lag yeah I mean
if you own a kit that goes together we
can we can measure actuator life right
oh yeah yeah so let's like let's plot
our cars yeah let's do a table in the
open violet readme by car with lower
actuator lag people if you want a better
open pilot experience yeah now we need
the same at the same theater safety I
think I'm not even like what I'm
detecting this what I'm worried about
particularly with that is like it's okay
if I'm fighting it but I'm afraid it's
gonna let go and then I'm gonna jerk the
wheel all right yes yes because I keep
putting torque right I'm a constant
torque now I need you need the same
thing I think we have this information
so we should be yeah we should think
about trying to make that safety club
more generic but well at least we can
make it like a library kind of thing
everybody want the same thing in there
in the vault as well mm-hm
so the danger is when you was a human
put torque on the wheel the PID loop
winds up and applies more and more
torque to fight you so we want that not
to happen yeah we want to basically yeah
like acknowledge the human over right so
it was nice that the first car we chose
to do this Honda already has this code
built and it's jak controller yeah and
it is alright that's the only way to
describe what we see
without doing anything if you try to
arrive with their with their own on one
side and let go there are sponsors like
super small town yeah yeah Tata
definitely was enter and default if you
remember the vault when we tried about
did the same thing as the tree otter I
said so I'm not surprised that this one
is like this yeah yes it was evolved and
the L cast note on this is probably the
same as the vault
I know
yeah
but it's solely like because the
actuators are so tight if you can just
totally feel that yes it's not driving
badly it's just like yeah you have well
so
oh it's disengaged oh yeah how'd that
happen what happened I know how to press
I get check
well because it's had pingpong of
Elena's og
oh no this a book yeah now this ain't
like acid oh I really we gotta we gotta
kill the cruise control - I don't like
yeah yeah yeah but that's gonna be easy
yeah thank you sir I can't even do it
now will expand me yeah how similar is
bald and messaging to 66 also laughter
Donnie is completely different so just
the CDC to also support the vault
message because I saw it there no I'm a
different boss you saw it oh the both
but supercruise and I cows are done with
like 0x1 52 52 52 and 54 oh yeah now
they're the Cadillac is different with
super who is it has two active safety
module active safety control modules and
they send different messages for
steering when Julie no control seems the
same stealing to try it but it only
seems like the same thing GM's
longitudinal controls very nice they
have one packet for the gas and one
packet for the brake yeah the best and
you command like the throttle right so
the Honda has a packet for the brake the
Honda brake packet is great the Civic is
is they're like the Utes like an ideal
Frank right yeah it's pretty good
someone's got a red light got him
I don't know later I like Amazon because
the flash really gives it away
gauging autopilot here the autopilot
swerve
[Music]
into that car oh yeah yeah yeah yeah
yeah this is like you see this loop this
is like our standard loop for testing
cars so I'm pretty well calibrated of
how they all perform
yeah so I have to give this one
it's probably the best
well with some tuning yeah yeah it's a I
mean it makes the model failures very
very apparent because he's died there
this is tight yeah
yeah it's less fucking anger yeah
but on the other hand every like
immediate feedback before it makes you
that I like more pretty you can predict
a little bit more water carry down yeah
I don't like not having my
alert triangle oh yeah car doesn't have
radar yes flexowriter
[Laughter]
yeah we need to figure this out yeah a
completely separate system or is that
using the sides like usually the sign is
a second
no in car manufactures wouldn't surprise
me if they like put the normal stock one
on there too but they're also cheap
which is an interesting what damn car a
vacuum like they're extremely cheap yet
they have like five ECU's to do
supercruise oh yeah replaced with one
cell phone yeah so this is a great
development platform yes Wow
you can get one to scope is for the best
about buy a Cadillac will actually wait
until we get the gas of the brake to
work and also wait until we get radars
but you can still Bible radar in duct
tape it to the front of
[Laughter]
all right scope ease that was riding a
Cadillac bye-bye
you're all quiet why I was so quiet
focus on the Caddy because it's the best
car
oh let's meet the models even open up
the model team you guys know like L from
Death Note that's kind of what the model
team is like you're a bot block which is
my prime now get here you'll come with
it my prime now get here oh my prime now
I got here
ah oh yeah you guys wanna see what I got
I'm prime now I can't show you some of
that secret but I can't show you what's
in the prime now bag for Samsung Evo
SSDs and we'll leave you with that hope
you enjoy the ride